hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast we
talk about ways for you to grow in your
life and in your business to make more
money as a coach trainer or Mentor now
today we're going to be trying a brand
new format that we have never done and
what we're going to do is I'm actually
going to be playing a video game while I
do the podcast and and I'm going to be
doing the podcast the same as I do but
I'm going to be talking while I'm doing
this and you can watch in the corner
while I do this if I need to switch over
to say you know chat GPT cuz we're going
to be doing something with chat GPT look
at that we can actually switch over to
it right here as far as this goes okay
so it's just like the regular podcast
but this is going to be the format that
we're going to do this and here's why as
I actually find that I can get into more
of a flow State and talk with you while
I'm doing something like playing a video
game so understand if you're listening
you're pretty much not going to be able
to tell any difference between the
podcast and in fact I think the podcast
is going to come across a lot better the
quality is going to be a lot better as
far as this goes but if you want to
watch uh what I'm actually playing while
I do this you can go to YouTube and
watch the YouTube version of the podcast
where it actually has me loading up a
game right now I'm playing Madden
football which is one of my favorite
things you might hear the sticks on my
controller just a little bit while I'm
talking as far as that goes but again
this is kind of the inaugural episode
where we're going to be trying this out
and we're going to just see how it works
if it doesn't work we're going to go
back to the other format as far as that
goes okay so listen I'm excited to to do
this to come with you today what I want
to talk about today is discipline and
this is a subject that a lot of people
are like you know oh my gosh and in fact
it's almost so juxtaposed to what I'm
doing right now some people see the idea
of playing video games as a lack of
discipline type of activ ity for me I
actually find that the more that I play
video games the more that I am alert and
aware by the way pause here I'm probably
not going to be looking at the camera
the whole time because I'm actually
looking at the screen in front of me
just above the camera so realize that
that is going to be the format while we
do this what we're going to be talking
about is in your business disciplining
yourself to do the stuff that maybe you
don't feel like and I was listening to a
Joe Rogan
podcast uh last night it was with the
Rock and they were talking about this
quote that really got me from Mike Tyson
Mike Tyson says this that discipline is
doing the thing that you don't want to
do with Incredible enthusiasm and
excitement while you do it and so that's
one of the principles that I think is
something that as business owners we
need to adapt to why is that because
there are things that we don't want to
do in our business there are things that
are not fun for us as far as that goes
you know it's not always sunshine and
rainbows building a business and so we
have to realize the reality of that is
that it's not always fun it's not always
going to be an exciting experience and
we're going to have setbacks we're going
to have moments where we feel like
quitting we're going to have times where
we want to give up we're going to feel
like the algorithm is against us and
everything is going against us and
things are not going how we quote
unquote wish that they could okay from
my experience here's the thing you know
when I started in my business one of the
biggest reasons why I actually struggled
to make money is I had this belief that
someday everything was just going to
come together for me and things were
going to finally work out how I wanted
them to and I was waiting rather for
things to get better before I started in
my business instead of just taking
advantage of how they were as they are
right now and so I want to just
encourage you in this take advantage of
the cards how you have been dealt them
we're not always going to get the deck
of cards how we want them to be
understand that things are not always
going to be how we would like them to be
at all times and that's perfectly okay
what you got to learn to do though is to
stay consistent when you run that
campaign and it doesn't produce the kind
of financial results that you want that
you keep on going that you keep on
moving forward as far as that goes kind
of like I just did with this football
game right here I'm actually playing
really well while I'm doing this which
is kind of impressive um so here's one
of the ways that I see that this
manifests for coaches mentors and
trainers is that a lot of the things
that we need to do in our business are
hard they're difficult they're simple to
learn but actually taking action with
them and actually doing
them is sometimes the hardest thing that
we have ever
done for instance building a landing
page it might feel like two steps
backwards for every step forward you
literally might feel like you're
regressing with every offer that you're
launching and I'm telling you as part of
building a business this is normal this
is part of the process and so realize
that we need to stop expecting things to
be different I understand maybe
everything in your life comes easy to
you I'm somebody that in my life I'm
extremely blessed and lucky that almost
everything that I try to do comes very
easy to
me except in business because it's the
great
equalizer business itself and creating
Financial wealth is the great equalizer
to where if you are great at almost
everything
you're probably still going to struggle
to make the kind of money that you want
to make in
business and I think that there's a sort
of belief especially in the beginning if
you've been successful making a few
sales in your business some of you are
listening you're like I haven't made a
single sale I've been at this for 17
years and haven't done anything so I
want to have empathy for both sides of
it number one by the way I think it's
actually harder if you're somebody who
has had financial success
why because it deceives you that the
next stage is going to be just as easy
as the previous stage at every stage of
your growth at every stage of you making
the kind of money that you want to
make there are going to be struggles
there are going to be things there are
going to be setbacks there are going to
be moments that you wished that things
could be just a little bit simpler just
a little bit easier that they would just
come just a little bit easier to
you you know the the and I liken this to
why I love to play play video games
because here's the thing you can always
grow in your skill set you can always
learn new strategies new tactics to get
better at the thing that you're doing
you know I'm playing an online game
right now with somebody who's actually
on the
internet that's actually a very hard
thing I've put in hundreds of hours into
this football video game over the years
for the last probably 10 years to get
better at it to improve at my skill set
and so what that does is that makes me
competitive it's the same business I've
been doing this in business for 21 years
some of y'all hear me talking like how
can I be coherent at creating content
like this while I'm also streaming live
online well it's because I've learned
how to connect how to communicate how to
talk that way how to be able to bring my
thoughts forward how to be able to even
tap into some of the areas of my mind
that are sometimes difficult to tap
into and multitask by being able to do
this and it's because I've been doing it
for a while in fact you know I used to
take business calls or I would be
playing video games because it actually
allowed me to tap into a part of my
brain that was more functional to be
able to come up with strategies that
people needed to hear and so what's cool
is I think the podcast is a very cool
outlet for me to be able to do that
moving forward again like I said the
video version this is a new format that
we're going to be do this I'm probably
not going to be talking as much about my
video games and stuff while we're doing
the podcast and things like that uh but
again this is the very first time that
I've ever done this format and so it's
kind of new for me and it's it's kind of
a fun
thing for instance I did not do very
well right there okay here's the
thing you're not always going to be
perfect you're not always going to make
the Right Moves you're not always going
to make the right place you're going to
have times where you think that things
are going to work out for you you and
then they don't what you have to do is
you have to build up your resilience
muscles your
ability to take the hits get back up
again and keep moving forward keep doing
the things that you know are going to
help you to succeed in your business
okay and so
understand that as a mentor as a trainer
as a coach
getting clients is not the easiest thing
in the world number one you need to grow
your email list if you're not growing
your email
list you don't have a
business if you're and and and and by
the way just growing the email list is
not enough for a business you need to
also get sales you need to also have
people buy from
you you need to
also learn how how to communicate in a
way that gets people to purchase the
things that you're doing one of the
biggest facades that I see that's out
there and it's by the way why I've
probably never done this before is I was
too concerned about looking good to
other people to be honest I might
completely lose respect for some people
by doing what I am doing right now live
on this podcast and I know that and I
understand that and I understand that
that's part of it but here's the thing
it's authentic for for me and I know
that those who connect with me they are
going to
appreciate the fact that I am being
myself showing up this way and it's
going to allow me to show up much better
and at a higher quality for people that
I am meant to connect with okay so
realize that not always is things going
to go your way learn to become more
resilient you might say Jeremiah I've
been resilient enough a lot of people
connect with me they're at their Wits
End they've been trying hard
enough I have a lot of empathy for that
and I want to tell you
this that
you can still
grow that you absolutely can still
improve move forward that you are not at
a place where you can't but one of the
things that we have to do is we have to
let go
of trying to make everything go our way
oh my gosh and this sounds
counterintuitive and this is the
counterintuitive advice that I think
that most people need to hear and why
I'm actually recording this podcast
episode you know I meet people all the
time and I tell them what they need to
do in their business and yet they still
don't do it they still think that
there's a different way to be successful
they still struggle to understand that
if they just changed how they did a few
things or if they worked on their mental
health you know I'm thinking of a client
of mine right now so much potential to
make millions of dollars and yet she's
afraid to show up on
camera that's an area that could be
grown
in but instead she's focusing on
everything else her business that's not
going to produce a
result and I feel sad because I see the
potential in her to be successful and
yet I also see the choice that she makes
every single
day every single time I see
her to stay stuck where she's
at and often times whenever we talk
there's tears and she cries and she says
I know I could do better but life is so
hard and I got to say say this listen if
life is that
hard it doesn't have to be that way you
can solve for
that you can learn to grow in your
strength in your resilience sometimes
it's going to take tough choices
changing the people you're listening
to changing your diet
even maybe you have health challenges I
totally understand that you know my mom
was given a year to live and yet she
still pressed through she didn't allow
what tried to kill her to stop her now I
don't have experience in that but I can
tell you this there are people right
now with less experience than
you with less
knowledge with less skill set with less
ability that are
succeeding far greater than you are why
because they they decided to just do the
thing that they've been not doing
they've decided to Simply
just keep moving forward and to not let
the thing that tried to break them that
tried to stop them that tried to keep
them from moving forward to defeat
them it's a choice it's a choice to
either stay stuck where we're at and
it's a choice to keep moving
forward and so I want to just encourage
you right now that if you're somebody
who feels like I've tried everything and
I just can't seem to get the
Breakthrough that I need in my life and
in my
business to realize that every single
day is a new experience it's a new
opportunity it's a clean slate we're
going into the new year right now and
maybe you're coming on your 18th year of
trying out I know a guy right now coming
up on his 18th year of trying to make
stuff work with the online marketing and
coaching
business but I can tell you
this the efforts are not in vain don't
give up keep moving forward and that's
where the discipline comes in to be
willing
to take the hits take the
punches and to make the decision you
know what I'm not going to let what to
break me what tried to stop me win that
I am going to be willing to yes I got a
touchdown I'm going to be willing to do
the tough
stuff that I'm going to be willing
to keep moving forward one of the
greatest things that I see that stops
people from
succeeding is this it's either
fear or Pride
you either have
fear of it not working out of you
wasting time missing out on
opportunities things not going how you
wanted to people rejecting you it not
working out how you want it to or your
pride won't let you show up at that
level your
arrogance and you might even say oh I'm
so humble listen I used to say that all
the time I'm so humble
notice I don't say that as much anymore
why because actually I know that I know
that I know where I'm called to go and
we need to address both of these things
both of these are just as
dangerous listen I want you to take
pride in the things that you can do
absolutely you need to have a high level
of self-esteem and self-belief and I
promise you this that if you work on
what's going on between your two ears
you're going to start to believe in
yourself more
don't ever stop believing in yourself
don't ever stop believing in what's
possible for you don't ever let somebody
tell you well you're you're being just a
little bit too uh you know uh
self-absorbed
self-motivated gosh this is ridiculous
this language that people have in their
coaching that they think helps people
and yet it stops them the level of
income that you can make is directly
correlated to your level of self-esteem
and you can grow in that and one of the
biggest things that can help you is
working on unraveling your triggers your
trauma the things that stop you from
making decisions perfectionism is one of
the single greatest things that stops
people and that's rooted in both either
Pride or fear maybe you grew up where
you had to do everything perfect in
order to be safe in your life or maybe
you don't want to show up in a way that
you feel is below you to other people
that you have a spirit of Excellence
that needs to show up and go forward at
a certain level I'm telling you both of
those are going to prevent you from
being successful so what you have to do
is you have
to
discipline
yourself to embrace the
journey to trust the process and this is
not in some woo woo way you need to have
gratitude for where you're at today that
you have air in your lungs and energy to
get up in the morning
and do the
thing just as I said in the beginning
that maybe is hard that maybe you hate
that maybe you don't want to do that
maybe you're avoiding with enthusiasm
and excitement and you also need to do
the thing that you're scared of many
times you need to do the thing that
maybe you've judged other people for
doing I think one of the greatest things
that I
see people judge coaches and
mentors for how they promote their
business and and there's a lot of cra
crappy coaches and mentors out there
that sell crappy products crappy
coaching that are not helping people and
so the level of standard that people
want to show up with Integrity actually
keeps them from being able to create the
kind of business that's going to make
them
successful because they don't want to be
quote unquote one of those people out
there I was also that way I had so much
judgment against coaches and mentors and
trainers that I had come across in my
life life and it was keeping me from
moving forward it was preventing me from
doing the very things that were going to
make me money and as soon as I got over
myself
literally and at the same time believed
in myself and at the same time stopped
being so self-critical and at the same
time I stopped punishing myself for the
mistakes that I made and I actually
embraced mistakes failures as a good
thing in my life as a teacher that every
single moment that maybe I struggled in
something it was a moment for growth it
was a moment where I could learn what I
don't know to progress
forward that it was a moment where I
didn't have to struggle where I didn't
have to
strive and where I could get back up
again to keep moving forward I'm telling
you my
friends we get so caught up distracting
ourselves from doing the very things are
going to make us money in our business
because we're avoiding the pain of
coming face to face with what I'm
talking about with you right
now people with so much talent so much
skill set I'm thinking about a a friend
of mine he's in the mortgage business so
much talent so much skill
set could be making millions of dollars
coaching and mentoring
people and yet I see him literally
choosing to not do the things that are
going to grow his
business literally choosing to not do
the things that could catapult him to
million-dollar coach
status and for whatever reason I don't
know it's an internal struggle maybe I
bet he's going to see this podcast I
might even share it with him what's up
dude you know what I'm talking about you
got so much potential man I believe in
you
you got so much potential to accomplish
greater than you could ever
imagine but there are things that you're
not doing that are keeping you from
being able to make the kind of money
that you want to make in a coaching and
course business because of possibly
either fear or standards that tie into
what I'm talking about right
now you have to
realize that sometimes we literally have
to
lower our
standards lower our standards of
excellence in order to create the kind
of business and the kind of income that
we want to make and this is not a
popular conversation why because it's
risky for me to talk about this it's
risky for me to say this because people
might misjudge misinterpret and misquote
what I just said to believe that I'm
encouraging you to put bad products out
there and to defraud people I'm not
encouraging that at all you need to put
quality stuff out there absolutely but
you need to stop being so
harsh about yourself about how
everything looks trying to look perfect
to everybody trying to make everything
perfect and realize that it's okay to
just show
up give it your best shot e even if
people hate you even if maybe it doesn't
produce the results that you want that
is going to move the needle forward for
you and then the second part of this is
when you do do that cuz I know people
who have broken past this level they're
in my coaching group you know I'm
thinking about multiple clients in my
coaching group right now they've
actually broken past
this but when they actually launch it's
not producing the kind of sales they
want and they feel like everything is
out to get
them realize that resilience that being
willing to stay the course continue the
process do the work even if it does not
produce the result that you want and yet
you still show up with the same belief
the same fortitude the same
ability to take yourself to the next
level is what is going to change
everything for
you I believe in you I believe that you
ever
absolutely can succeed I believe that
you
absolutely can take things to the next
level in your life and in your
business you don't have to let these
things stop
you often times the reason why it stops
US is internally we have these beliefs
we have these things that we're trying
to avoid happening and that's one of the
questions I literally have it written
right in front of me in my office cuz I
have to remember this everything comes
back to this one question and really
it's taking me about this whole time of
the podcast to get here is I want you to
ask yourself this if you find yourself
facing setbacks if you find
yourself throwing up your hands getting
angry when things don't go how you want
and I totally get it like I have empathy
for that of course when things don't go
how you want when people reject you when
people don't buy from you when you
invest in your business when you run ads
and it doesn't produce the sales that
you want when you do a whole campaign
when you host a webinar and people don't
buy from you oh my gosh and maybe you've
been doing it for 10 years 12 years
maybe you relocated your whole family to
a city to start something to start a
movement that you felt called to do and
it didn't produce the results that you
wanted or you're not quite where you
want it to be yet I can tell you this
don't give up in doing the right things
don't give up in continuing
to move the ball
forward you can learn new skill sets but
I got to tell you this it's going to
take you doing things that maybe you
have not tried before it's going to take
you showing up on a new level going into
the new year to discipline yourself to
not let fear or Pride or ego stop you
from showing up again attitude of
gratitude
amazing that's the perfect Foundation
but then we also got to do the work we
also got to do the stuff that we have
been avoiding the stuff that we've been
putting off the stuff that we have been
walking away from the stuff that we have
been making excuses for again and again
and again and again and
again and and and and I and I meet
people so
often they're like Jeremiah I'm not
making excuses I've just been doing all
the right things and it's not working
can I tell you this I meet people all
the time they tell me well listen you
know I'm just trusting in the Lord's
will in this process or I'm just
trusting in the
process and and and by the way I
literally just said five minutes ago to
trust the
process but there's a side of
it that if you get anything from what I
talk about here
today is going to be the game changer
for
you
you have to do the hard stuff you have
to do the stuff that you're putting off
there might be a list and what I like to
do is I like to make a list what I call
my top three what are my top three
things that I need to do in my
life what are the top three goals that I
have that I would like to change in my
life and how can I start to move things
forward to move the needle forward to
start to make those things come to pass
and then what I do is I reverse engineer
what those things look like so like for
instance for me in my
business eight figure sales that's over
$10 million a year in
sales and again I'm not talking about
like 10 million in profit cuz really I
would end up investing a lot of that
back into my business or into other
Investments or things to grow my bottom
line but the game changes when you hit
over a million dollars a month and I
know people that have done that I have
helped people do that I have built
multiple coaching businesses that other
people own and operate that I was the
CEO of that I was Consulting and I help
them get to that
level but my own business isn't making
that much today we have a seven figure
Revenue business it's incredible it's
amazing we're making a ton of money
we're impacting a ton of people's lives
that's why I have the confidence to
literally show up and play a video game
while I'm doing a podcast I'll tell you
you you don't have to wait until you
accomplish things to have the confidence
to do the things that you want to do and
if there was one thing that I wish that
I did sooner was just doing whatever the
heck I wanted regardless of what anybody
thinks about me and listen I'm still
growing in this area I'm not perfect at
it I still struggle at it I still fail
at it to this
day but I continue to move forward one
of those things is this
I could not care less anymore what
anybody thinks about me if anybody
listens to my podcast they get offended
they get turned off of me they get
pissed off they want to uh sit down with
me and confront me about how wrong I am
listen that used to destroy me when
people would do that and it and it and
it used to happen wow that was a
terrible Play What Was I
Thinking oh my gosh yeah this is like
the real chief right here
right I thought I thought I was the
quarterback right
there but I have to get back up again
and and again just like in this game
keep doing the things that I know are
going to help me keep doing the things
that are going to move me forward what's
another thing that I want to do I want
to
be
less
reactive and
More in
encouraging also less critical you might
notice maybe today I might have sounded
maybe a little bit critical some of you
are hearing this maybe you feel like I
was talking directly about
you you know I shared this podcast with
a few people that maybe I was using some
examples but it's because I know that
it's going to help those people succeed
in their life to reach those goals that
they have we're going to go for it
here we're going to try this play
again you don't have to struggle but
it's going to take
you
doing
what you're not and what I look at is I
look at stuff from a six month
perspective what are the things that 6
months ago I said that I was going to do
that I am still not doing
and what I do is as soon as I can tap
into that it allows me to truly start to
make the
decisions that was it we just we we we
made first down it allows me to truly
make the decisions to say okay I said I
was going to do this 6 months ago and
this is one of the strategies that I
would say going into the new year that
is going to help a lot of you
succeed if you have things that you've
been putting off that you know that you
need to do and things are not working
out you need to start to go to work in
reverse engineer what needs to change
what behaviors might need to be adjusted
to move the needle forward for you what
was preventing you over the last 6
months from doing the thing that you
said that you would start doing 6 months
ago and then I also look at it 12 months
ago for me a big one my son was born
he's about to be a year old and yet
there are things that I have struggled
with for the last year that I'm like no
more I got to reverse engineer what that
is and what I have done usually by doing
this I break it down into
6mon 12
month and 18mon increments and generally
for me by doing this by being very
self-aware of what I told myself let's
bring this down here what I told myself
that I was going to
do 6 12 and 18 months ago by the time 18
months rolls
around there's breakthrough that has
happened one of the biggest issues that
we have is to why breakthrough doesn't
happen is we're not asking for help
we're trying to go about it on our own
we're trying to figure out things that
maybe we've never done before on our own
brand new we've never tried these things
before they're completely new
experiences for
us sometimes you you got to humble
yourself and say listen I don't know how
to do the thing that I need to do that
is going to change everything for me and
I need to learn from somebody who knows
how to do the thing that I need to learn
how to do to keep moving
forward if you find yourself to where
there are things that you committed to
do 6 months
ago 12 months ago 18 months ago and by
the way don't let anybody pressure you
in these things I want these to be by
your choice there are things right now
that there are people possibly even
people listening to this podcast that
think that I should have done 18 to 12
months ago that to be honest I have
chosen you know what not a priority for
me you need to own your choices you need
to take ownership over your choices
there's a great book that I love called
Extreme ownership that talks about this
about taking ownership over where we're
at and realizing that everything that
we're experiencing right now we have
chosen
and realize that it is an explicit
choice to do something and to not do
something it is an explicit choice to
not ask for help and to just sit on your
bum and hope things change for
you and we can choose differently in our
lives we do not have to repeat the same
cycle that we came into 2023 with I'm
telling you this the economy is
shifting the world in 12 months from now
as we go into 2025 we're going to know
two things one in the United States who
is going to be president for the next
four years into
2029 artificial intelligence is going to
hit a critical mass Breaking Point
that's beyond what anybody can imagine I
believe that robotics is going to have a
huge breakthrough coming into this next
year and so we we have to decide if
there are goals that we have and it
takes
us impacting new people growing our
community that there may never be a
moment in time similar to what we have
today and that things a are going to get
a lot harder after a year from now and
if we put off these things another year
from now we may never have the chance or
opportunity that we have here today to
do the things that we need to
do now of course I understand God can do
great things he can do big things and I
truly believe in that but here I'm the
I'm the type of person that says that I
trust God as if he's in control and I go
to work as if I am and it's not that I'm
not trusting him but I'm doing
everything in my
ability to do at least what I
can to not let my situation control me
you know I know people right now they
don't even go to the doctor cuz they
think that that
is not trusting
God they might even have cancer but they
refuse to do the things that they can do
they refuse to even eat healthily they
refuse to change their lifestyle because
you know what the Lord went and I'm like
oh my gosh that is literally complete
irresponsibility and a complete
misinterpretation of the truth yes God
can do great
things
but we also need to also do the stuff
that we can do and I don't want to overp
spiritualize this because this podcast
isn't a quote unquote spiritual or even
Christian podcast even though I'm
somebody who is spiritual and and a
Christian but I got to say
this
sometimes I and I remember a a guy that
I love listening to uh will Ford taught
this for years some people are waiting
for a move of God when actually God is
waiting for you to
move
okay some of y'all have have been
meditating your way trying to succeed
when in fact you got to do something
that maybe you've been putting
off so as we go into the new year listen
I fully encourage being an
embodying
faith I fully
encourage relaxing your nervous system
doing all these
things but if we sit on our Duff and we
do
nothing with the with the resources that
have been given to
us with the opportunities that been
presented to
us don't expect a different
outcome from those
situations because we are essentially
choosing for things to happen that way
and I can tell you this my friends it
doesn't doesn't have to be that way you
can make a decision today to say you
know what I am no longer going to allow
my pride fear or ego to keep me from
doing the stuff that is going to help me
succeed I am no longer going to let my
fears and worries and doubts I'm no
longer going to let oh gosh I'm going to
say it I'm no longer going to let my
faith
religiously keep me from doing what I
know that I should do that I know what I
am called to
do I'm no longer going to let my
belief maybe you're somebody who
believes in in the universe you believe
in crystals or what CU I got a lot of
people who listen to me and I'm not I'm
not here to to say I tell you what I
believe in but I'm not here to tell you
to to to stop believing in something
that that you think is working for
you but belief only goes
halfway you got to believe that you can
do it absolutely and then you got to
actually do the work you got to actually
show up you got to actually commit to
actually doing the thing that maybe
you've been putting off that you know
that is going to help move things
forward for you and here's the thing
often times when we set out to do this
and and this is my kind of my last Point
as we wind down
here when we do those things they don't
actually turn out how we would hope they
would they don't actually go how we
expected them to and that's why most of
the time we give up or we say oh well
maybe it wasn't meant to
be no because you have just started to
gain momentum and so don't quit the
momentum simply because you've started
simply because things aren't working out
how you've wanted them
to keep
moving forward
keep doing the thing that you
know that you need to do and it takes a
great level of self-awareness and maybe
you don't have the answer to this right
now maybe you're listening to this and
you're like Jeremiah I've been trying to
do the thing that is going to move me
forward for years and I'm doing my best
we've seen progress can I tell you
this what if you shortened the timeline
maybe you've been doing this long enough
and you have a pace that you've been
doing things at what if you shortened
that timeline instead of expecting it to
take you another 10 years you decided
you know what I'm going to work as best
as I can to take this to the next level
for
me over the
next 5 years or even 3 years or even
year what if you were able to take the
stuff that would normally take you 5 to
10 years to do and you got them done in
just one year this is actually a concept
that I have heard from some of the most
successful people that I've ever met is
when they actually approached this
decision and said you know what what if
it doesn't have to take as long as I
think it does what if I could speed some
things up and what if by speeding things
up maybe things didn't work out but in
the big picture they happened faster see
I think sometimes we're afraid of making
a mess we're afraid of things not going
how we want and our pride and ego keeps
us from doing the things that we need to
do because we're afraid of quote unquote
losing out or things not going how we
wish that they could can I tell you
this that that's one of the single
greatest areas that you can solve for
that's going to change your life that
that's one of the single greatest areas
that if you just started doing some of
the things that you've been putting off
that you've been neglecting that you've
been taking longer to do and you just
started doing some of those things
even if they seem hard even if failure
literally might be imminent you know I
listened to interviews with people like
Elon Musk or Jeff Bezos and they say you
know what chances of success were less
than
10% but I knew that I needed to
try what if you started doing things
that you actually had a low probability
of success
for and you sure you did higher
probability activities
what if you asked for help even if the
probability of somebody helping you or
saying yes was Zero instead of worrying
about trying to manage maintain and
control the choices and the decisions
that other people need to make and you
started to become okay with possibly
things not working out and you started
to be okay with moving forward even if
things didn't go how you wanted or
expected them
to and you actually did the thing that
and maybe while I'm saying this there's
a there's things in your life that you
know that you need to do it's just it's
too agitating to do it it just creates
too much anxiety for you and and you've
been trying to maintain your peace for
long enough can I tell you this that one
of the biggest mistakes that I see
people make is there are things that
they could be doing that will transform
their life that will create the kind of
business that will create the kind of
community that they're even called
to and yet their need for things quot
quote to go how they expect it or want
it is keeping them from moving the ball
forward because their their ability to
risk it all their ability for things to
accept that when things don't work out
that they aren't bad that they're not
wrong that it's actually okay to do
something and it not go how you want it
to that it's actually
okay to try something out and to fail at
it and that that's actually part of the
process of success that embracing total
failure is actually how we
succeed and that one of the biggest
mistakes that people make is believing
that everything should always work
out well it's always worked out for me
before and yet you find yourself coming
up against the plateau you find yourself
coming up against the brick wall you
find yourself repeating the same
Mountain over and over and over again
that you thought that you had learned
from that you thought that you had
mastered that you thought that you had
overcome and yet you end up repeating
the same mistake again and it feels like
it's five steps forward three steps
back we have have to make a
decision to keep moving
forward we have to make the decision to
get back up again to become resilient to
rebound even
when things might not work out how we
want it to even when things don't go
quote unquote how we think they
should and to become okay with just
trying it out
out you know in software development
there's this term called an alpha and a
Beta release just to beta test an idea
you know I meet people all the time that
there's this phrase I hear people say in
media you know you only got one chance
at a first impression I a measure twice
cut once type of
person can I tell you this that for most
of the people that I meet and that I
work with that that's actually the
greatest thing that stops them from
succeeding and reaching their goals is
because they're waiting for
certainties they're waiting to feel like
okay I know for certain now that this is
going to work when in fact the way that
they're actually going to get that
certainty is by taking risks by doing
things by becoming okay with
failing like I've pretty much done at
this football game right here I'm going
to lose this game but you know what it
was a great experience I'm not angry I'm
not emotional I'm not upset by it
because I know that the more that I play
that the more that I continue to grow in
my skill set you know I noticed a few
sloppy moves that I made that maybe I
could do better in this
game and yet I still got back up again
and I'm still going to play another
round again and I'm still going to keep
moving forward and I'm not going to let
what tried to stop me defeat me moving
into 2024 oh look at that there's
another
touchdown you know some of
y'all your goals your life and your
business look kind of like this football
game right
here and thanks for those that have
stuck with me watching through this
whole
thing sometimes we just got to accept
the fact that things don't go how we
wish they would even if they look
certain it's okay to get back up again
it's okay to
not
feel
well you want to feel the pain you want
to let it like feel it for a little bit
but then you move forward you don't let
it defeat you you don't let it stop you
you change the meaning and the
choices that you put behind those
things and that my friends is one of the
greatest strategies that I believe is
going to help you succeed if you are a
mentor coach trainer Pastor leader
business leader
this will make you more successful you
will be able to impact more people and
as we go into 2024 I want to inspire
you number one if this episode has hit
you deeply I want you to share it with
some
people don't hold this back yourself
share it with somebody that you know
it's going to help impact them and
number two I want you to make a list of
what are your top three things that you
want to accomplish what are your top
three goals you know number number three
for
me I want to
have $1
million in my stocks portfolio you know
my mom in the last year she's in the
same industry as me coaching and
mentoring she's got a portfolio that's
worth over five 5 million in the last
year I want to have 1
million why because I know that that is
going to be the next level so I got to
look look at what are some choices and
decisions that I need to make to become
less reactive less critical more
encouraging to increase my overall sales
to $10 million a year and to have $1
million in my investment
account and then I got to work backwards
and look at
okay what have I not been doing for the
last 6 months because I actually had
these goals six months
ago what have I not been doing for the
last 6 months that I need to start doing
that I've been putting off that I've
been neglecting that I've been avoiding
doing what are the tough decisions that
I need to make and what are the risks
that I need to take just to see what
happens to keep moving forward and so my
friends as we go into 2024 I hope this
encourages you to start taking more
risks to start doing some of those
things that you've been afraid of start
doing those things that maybe you've had
previous standards of excellence that
have prevented you from putting yourself
out there and doing them and adopt this
alpha or beta release approach where
you're willing to beta test and launch
something that might even be under
development that might still be
incomplete that might not be a fully
fleshed out idea but you just want to
see what happens you just want to see
how it resonates with people it's kind
of what I did today with this episode
gosh I have no idea how this is going to
resonate one of my longest podcast
episodes but my goodness it was some
good
content
maybe we'll do it again maybe we won't
maybe they won't all be this way maybe
some of them
will you do not have to let what tried
to break you defeat you you can succeed
if you have a goal in a
dream and you apply this process and you
take a look at okay what decisions have
I avoided in the last six to 12 months
that have stopped me from doing these
things and I and listen I know what some
of those decisions are for me and we've
started to implement
changes one of the biggest ones is my
communication with others I have allowed
the excuse that I struggle with
communication like direct one-on-one
communication I can do I can do group
talks like this but when it comes to
one-on-one communication gosh I actually
kind of struggle with that a little bit
and I know that I can grow in that area
and I know that it's going to help me go
to the next
level so listen I believe in you and I
know that you can succeed and this can
be your year don't let what try to
defeat you what try to stop you break
you keep moving forward share this
episode with somebody and I'd love to
hear from you your thoughts after this
either send me a comment send me a
message
DM we'll talk soon grow your life
everybody have a good
[Music]
[Applause]
one